Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection 1790-2022 PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Motion Picture and Theater Posters, 1790-2022
  - Subseries VI.A Motion Picture Posters, 1914-2022
    - Carl Laemmle presents Harry Langdon and Slim Summerville in "See America Thirst", 1930 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      The advertisement is in two pieces and features the commedians, Harry Langdon and Slim Summerville, leaning against a lamp pole with an inset image of the actress, Bessie Love.
    - Carl Laemmle presents "East is West", 1930 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      The advertisement features a woman dressed in a stylized kimono. "East is West" is a movie of the stage play of the same name by Samuel Shipman and John B. Hymer. The Universal Picture was a Monta Bell Production, produced by Carl Laemmle, Jr. with Lupe Velez, Lewis Ayes, and Edward G. Robinson.
    - Carl Laemmle presents "Dracula", 1931 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      Advertisement was made in the U.S.A. and features an image of Dracula with an open cape holding a swooning model. "Dracula, a Universal Picture, was produced by Carl Laemmle, Jr., based on the novel by Bram Stoker.
    - "David and Dora in their little love-nest." from David Copperfield, 1935 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      Bottom front of still: "Country of Origin USA." "David Copperfield from the novel by Charles Dickens".
    - "The Rookery -- Boyhood home of Little David" from David Copperfield, 1935 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      On bottom front of still: "Country of Origin U.S.A." and "David Copperfield from the novel by Charles Dickens".
    - "Bette Davis, Miriam Hopkins in Warner Bros. "Old Acquaintance" at the Hollywood Theater, 1943 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      Advertisement strip copyrighted by Nathan Rubin Ads. Also includes a small advertisement for the Strand movie palace.
    - "Cary Grant in Frank Capra's 'Arsenic and Old Lace'" at the Strand movie palace, 1944 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      Advertisement strip by Nathan Rubin for "Broadway's Happiest Fun Show! at the Strand". On screen, "Arsenic and Old Lace" with Cary Grant (pictured), Raymond Massey, Jack Carson, Peter Lorre; on stage, Charlie Barnet, his orchestra and gala revue.
    - Columbia Pictures presents "The Killer that Stalked New York", 1950 (Folder OS FF 06.1-04)
      The poster is copyrighted by the Columbia Pictures Corp. in 1950. The film starred Evelyn Keyes, Charles Korvin, and William Bishop. Screenplay by Harry Essex, based on Cosmopolitan Magazine article by Milton Lehman, directed by Earl McEvoy and produced by Robert Cohn. The plot of the film involves a smallpox outbreak.
    - The Rank Organisation presents a Val Guest Production "80,000 Suspects", 1963 (Folder OS FF 06.1-04)
      The poster was printed in Great Britain. The film starred Claire Bloom, Richard Johnson, Yolande Donlan, and Cyril Cusack. Val Guest wrote the screenplay and directed the film. It was based on a novel by Elleston Trevor, and the film was shot in CinemaScope. The plot of the film involves a smallpox outbreak.
    - ABC Television Network poster announcing the airing of "Roots", 1977 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      The poster features images of the starring actors set out by the generations. It was a David L. Wolper Production based on the Alex Haley novel "Roots," about slavery in America. It was first was shown on TV on 8 consecutive nights from January 23 to January 30, 1977.
    - Broadway Dancer in Art Deco fashion, undated (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      A two part advertisement for Broadway by The Hennegan Company of Cincinnati, Ohio. It features an image of a broadway dancer with a second piece with "Broadway" written on it that could be attached to the dancer as a skirt.
    - "Bros" poster signed by Nicholas Stoller, Billy Eichner, and Luke Macfarlane, 2002 (Folder OS FF 06.1-05)
  - Subseries VI.B Theater Posters, 1790-1945
    Many of the posters in this subseries were individually cataloged in the library's catalog Bobcat in 2017.
    Researchers can use the partial call phrase "PR-055-06" to search for these items.
    This subseries includes posters advertising individual plays operettas, minstrel shows, musicians, specialty acts, and dance companies. The bulk of the series dates from the late nineteenth to the early twentieth century.
    Most of the posters are arranged by date, and then alphabetically by theater; a small number are arranged by type of entertainment. There is some overlap of contents.
    - Theaters, 1820-1829 (Folder FF 06-42)
      Chatham Gardens
      Chatham Theatre
      Park Theatre
      Thomas Langdon's Columbian Gardens
    - Theaters, 1850-1859 (Folder FF 06-43)
      Academy of Music
      Astor Place
      Bowery
      Broadway
      Brougham's
      Burton's
      Castle Garden
      Ha! Market Theater
      Melodeon
      Metropolitan
      National
      Niblo's Garden
      St. Charles
      Thomas' Opera House
      Wallack's
    - Theaters, 1860-1869 (Folder FF 06-44)
      American Theatre
      Fox's Old Bowery
      Hitchcock's National Concert Hall
      Laura Keene's Theatre
      Mechanic's Hall
      New Bowery
      New York Theatre
      Olympic Theatre
      St. Charles Theatre
      Stuyvesant Hall
      Wall's Theatre
      Wallack's Theatre
      Winter Garden
    - Theaters, 1870-1879 (Folder FF 06-45)
      Booth's
      Boston
      Columbia Opera House
      Cooper Institute, Great Hall
      Dramatic Hall
      Fifth Avenue
      Fourth Street
      Harry Hill's Variety
      Haverly's 14th Street
      Heller's Wonder Theater
      Morrisania
      New Third Avenue
      Olympic
      Palais Royal Garden
      Parisian Varieties
      Parisian Vaudeville
      Robinson Hall
      Ryan's Vaudeville
      St. James
    - Theaters, 1870-1879 (Folder FF 06-46)
      Broadway (various)
      Bryant's Opera House
      Burton Dramatic Association
    - Theaters, 1870-1879 (Folder FF 06-47)
      Eagle Theatre
      Fifth Avenue Theatre
      Globe
      Grand Opera House
      London Theatre
      Lyceum
    - Theaters, 1870-1879 (Folder FF 06-48)
      National Theater
      Olympic Theater
      Park Theater
      Tony Pastor's
      Standard
      Theatre Comique
      Union Square
    - Theaters, 1870-1879 (Folder FF 06-49)
      Wood's Museum
    - Theaters, 1880-1889 (Folder FF 06-50)
      Abbey's Park Theatre
      Association Hall
      Atlantic Garden
      Bijou Opera House
      Booth's Theatre
      Boston Theatre
      Broadway Opera House
      Broadway Theatre (various)
      Chickering Hall
      Daly's
    - Theaters, 1880-1889 (Folder FF 06-51)
      Fourteenth Street Theatre
      Germania Theatre
      Globe Theatre
      Harlem Music Hall
      Irving Place Theatre
      Leland Opera House
      Madison Square
      New Park Theatre
      Palmer's Theatre
      Parker's American Theatre
      Pastor's Theatre
    - Theaters, 1880-1889 (Folder FF 06-52)
      Star
      Windsor
    - Theaters, 1890-1899 (Folder FF 06-53)
      Abbey's Theatre
      Amburg Theatre
      Broadway Theatre
      Brooklyn Academy of Music
      The Casino
      Daly's Theatre
      Empire Theatre
      Garden Theater
      Garrick Theatre
      Harrigan's Theatre
      Harris Academy of Music
      Hawaiian Opera House
      Herald Square Theatre
      Knickerbocker Theatre
      Koster and Bial's Music Hall
      Lamb's Theatre
      Lyceum Theatre
      Madison Square Theatre
      Manhattan Opera House
      Metropolitan Opera House
      Miner's Fifth Avenue Theatre
      Pastor's 14th Street
      Proctor's Theatre
      Standard Theatre
      Star Theatre
      Union Square Theatre
      Victoria
      Weber and Field's Music Hall
      Windsor Theatre
    - Theaters, 1900-1945 (Folder FF 06-54)
      Adelphi Theatre
      Amberg Theatre
      Astor Theatre
      Belasco Theatre
      Bronx Theatre
      Carnegie Hall
      Century Theatre
      Cort Theatre
      Deutsche's Theatre
      Forty-Eighth (48th) Street Theatre
      Fourteenth (14th) Street Theatre
      Garden Theatre
      Harlem Opera House
      Hollis Street Theatre
      Hudson Theatre
      Montauk Theatre
      Morosco Theatre
      Murray Hill Theatre
      Neighborhood Playhouse
      New Amsterdam Theatre
      Orpheum Theatre
      Princess Theatre
      Provincetown Players
      Pythian Theatre
      Republic Theatre
      Shubert Theatre
      Stuyvesant Theatre
      Thirty-Ninth (39th) Street Theatre
      Tribune Theatre
      Wadsworth Theatre
      Yorkville Casino
      Yorkville Theatre
    - Theatrical Productions - Lectures, 1841-1890 (Folder FF 06-55)
      Subjects include health, human anatomy, history, literature, and travel. Some are advertised as illustrated lectures which feature paintings, photographs, and panoramas.
    - Theatrical Productions - Minstrel Shows, 1842-1895 (Folder FF 06-56)
      Material advertising minstrel shows and entertainments that include performers in blackface makeup.
    - Theatrical Productions - Minstrel Shows, 1842-1895 (Folder FF 06-57)
    - Theatrical Productions - Minstrel Shows, 1842-1895 (Folder FF 06-58)
      Material related to minstrel shows and performers in blackface makeup. Items in this folder are especially FRAGILE.
    - Theatrical Productions - Musicians and Concerts, 1840-1925 (Folder FF 06-59)
      Posters advertising musical performances at various New York City venues.
    - Theatrical Productions - 7th Regiment and 28th Regiment Association Productions, 1862 (Folder FF 06-60)
- Series VII. World War I Posters, 1914-1920
  The World War I Poster series, dates from circa 1914 to 1920, and consists of posters, pictorial sheets and related ephemera used by governments and organizations during the first World War to persuade citizens to enlist in various branches of the armed service, buy bonds, conserve food and fuel, provide relief, and generally support the war and aid efforts.
  There is a separate inventory for this series, found at this link: World War I Posters
- Series VIII. World War II Posters, 1941-1946; 500 item(s) (approximately)
  The collection is comprised of approximately 500 posters related to various aspects of the United States's mobilization for World War II. Topics include war financing (war bonds, donations); conservation and rationing; recruitment for the military, including a target audience of women for the Women's Army Auxiliary Corps (WAACs), and the Nursing Corps.
  The World War II Posters series has a separate inventory found at this link: World War II Posters
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 1896-2021
  Subjects include: Women's activism/rights, Anti-war protests, Public health, AIDS, Transportation, and LGBTQ+ rights.
  - Subseries IX.1. Chronological, 1896-2021
    The subseries includes a variety of subjects, too few of each to classify within one of the other topical subseries. All posters in this subseries are listed individually.
    Arrangement
    The subseries is arranged in rough chronological order.
    - American Water Color Society. 29th Annual Exhibition., 1896 (Folder FF 09-01)
      Poster designed by George Wharton Edwards. Exhibition held at the National Academy of Design. On back, "The Harry A. Ogden Collection of The New York Historical Society. October 20, 1936."
    - Advertisement for a weekly, Truth, sold everywhere., circa 1896 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Poster features pictures of McKinley and Bryan and offers $20 in gold or silver if you are wiser than McKinley or Bryan.
    - "Never mind Chimmie, termorrow yer sells Journals..." 2 news boys (newsies), circa 1900 (Folder FF 09-03)
    - "Official Summary of Electoral Votes cast for each President of the United States of America.", 1911 (Folder FF 09-03)
      The chart of electoral votes from 1789-1908 was compiled by the Clerk of the U.S. House of Representatives. Also explains how electors are chosen and how many will be apportioned to each state in 1913.
    - "Instruction to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1905 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Printed by Martin B. Brown, Co. Printers. The poster sets out 7 rules and Chapter 693, An Act to Amend the Penal Code. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are John R. Voorhis, Charles B. Page, John Maguire, and Michael J. Dady.
    - Independence League Watcher's Tally Card, 1906 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Watcher's Tally Card for New York Election held November 6, 1906. On back, there is a grid with Parties going across the top and the elected positions down the side. There are tally marks filling in the grid. Acquisition date (?) on front: Dec. 2, 1932.
    - "Department of Health", 1907 (Folder FF 09-03)
      On the back, there are excerpts from a letter from Dr. Sydney Carney, Jr. dated July 3, 1907. The letter explains that Dr. Thomas Darlington (the donor of the poster) told Dr. Carney that these signs were fastened over the street sweeping carts in New York City after the Board of Health took charge of removing garbage from the streets when the street cleaning drivers went on strike. Acquisition date: Dec. 23, 1910.
    - "Meeting of Teachers" on the subject of "Teachers' Bill", 1907 May 22 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Printed by Press of Kiesling Brothers. Taxpayers were also invited to the meeting held at Morris High School at 166th Street & Boston Road. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Third Annual Outing of the Jackson Democratic Club of the 34th District, 1909 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Printed by The Kiesling Company. A picture of Arthur H. Murphy, Executive Member of the Board of Directors, is featured on the poster. The poster also lists the Officers, the Board of Directors and the members of the Reception Committee, the Outing Committee, and the Games Committee. The outing was held on August 16, 1909, at Witzel's Point View Grove. On front, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - The Republican Club / 35th Assembly District Outing and Games Day, 1909 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Thomas W. Whittle, Chairman of the Board of Governors of The Republic Club/35th Assembly District, is pictured on the poster. The rest of the Officers and Board of Governors are listed as are the names of all on the Committee of Arrangements. The Games were held on Sept. 11, 1909, at M.J. Kane's Clason Point View-on-the-Sound. On the front, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Bronx Church House (171st Street and Fulton Avenue) The Night of Nights - Basket Ball and Dance, [1910s] (Folder FF 09-02)
      Poster printed by Henry Emmerson. Night included two basketball games and a dance. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Board of Education, City of New York presentation poster of the Independence Day Committee, 1915 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Depicts a series of vignettes of important events in American history, including the end of the Civil War and the building of the Panama Canal. Stamped on back, "The Henry A. Ogden Collection of the New York Historical Society. October 20, 1936".
    - "Instructions to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1915 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co. The instructions include 3 steps and Article 74 of the Penal Code is set out below the instructions. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are Edward F. Boyle, Moses M. McKee, James Kane, and Jacob A. Livingston. Acquisition date (?) on front: Dec. 2, 1932 and "Child".
    - "Instructions to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1916 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Poster printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co. The poster sets out 5 steps of instructions and an amended version of Article 74 of the Penal Code. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are Edward F. Boyle, Moses M. McKee, James Kane, and Jocaob A. Livingston. Acquisition date (?) on front: Dec 1, 19_2.
    - "Instructions to Voters" (New York City Board of Elections), 1917 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co. The instructions set out 3 steps for voting and Article 74 of the Penal Code. The Commissioners of the Board of Elections are Edward F. Boyle, Moses M. McKee, James Kane, and Jacob A. Livingston.
    - Federal Registration for Election District 17, Assembly District 35, 1917 (Folder FF 09-03)
      Federal registration dated June 5, 1917. "Register Here".
    - The Mayflower Compact, 1920 (Folder FF 09-01)
      Printed by Tiffany & Co. in 1920 on the three hundredth anniversary of the signing of "The Compact". On back, in pencil, "Presented by Frank B. Porter November 30, 1920."
    - Advertisement of The Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts Summer School in Chester Springs, Chester County, Pennsylvania., [1920s] (Folder FF 09-04)
      The poster features photographs of the studio classes and grounds at the summer school. Board, lodging and tuition was $15 per week.
    - Sweet Land of Liberty, Of Thee I Sing, 1921 (Folder FF 09-01)
      Removed from folder for an exhibition on 1/18/2020. Poster was designed by Wallace Robinson and printed by John J. Cusick.
    - Red Cross Advertisement, 1921 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Poster design features a red cross superimposed over 1921. Aquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 1, 1947.
    - Advertisement for Woman's Home Companion for July featuring best photograph of Mrs. Roosevelt., 1921 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by The Crowell Publishing Company. Photograph of Mrs. Roosevelt copyrighted in 1903 by George Prince. Acquisition date (?) on front: June 4, 1921.
    - The (Warren G.) Harding Memorial, 1923 (Folder FF 09-01)
      The poster gives dates for the memorial from December 9th through the 16th of 1923 and states, "subscription memberships received here". The poster was designed by Dan Smith after photo by Edmonston.
    - "The Government would be grateful if you would -- Shop Early, Wrap Carefully, Address Plainly and Mail Promptly" (Postmaster General poster), 1923-1929 (Folder FF 09-02)
      Printed by the Government Printing Office. On top, labelled as "N.Y. Poster 10-C". Harry S. New is the Postmaster General on the poster. He served from 1923-1929. On back, in pencil, is "EB Child/39".
    - Appeal by the New York Public Library Staff Association., 1924 (Folder FF 09-01)
      The appeal is asking the public to lobby the Board of Estimate to keep the public libraries up to standard with increased salaries to the trained staff and increases in the volumes of books. Poster designed by R. Ferryman.
    - Huguenot-Walloon Tercentenary Settlement of New Netherland Celebration Proclamation of New York State, 1924 (Folder FF 09-04)
      The Proclamation by Alfred E. Smith, Governor of New York, designated the month of May 1924 for the observance of the Tercentenary of the Founding of New Netherland. A note at the bottom states that the U.S. Government has issued a commemorative half dollar coin on sale for $1.00. Aquisition date (?) on back: March 17, 1924.
    - La Morte Di Wilson in La Nazione della Sera [Italian], 1924 (Folder FF 09-04)
      Newspaper supplement to the Feruary 4, 1924 edition of La Nazione della Sera. Pagine 6.
    - Announcement of Albany's Tercentenary 3 Day Historical Pageant., 1924 (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster printed by J.B. Lyon Company Printers, Albany. Celebration took place from June 1-3, 1924. Aquisition date (?) on front: June 11, 1924.
    - "United States of America First Defense Test Day", 1924 (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster was lithographed by 1st Lt. David Klein, O.R.C., 42 Ross St., Brooklyn, N.Y. The first "Defense Test" day was scheduled for September 12, 1924.
    - "Fete de la Tour Eiffel", 1924 (Folder FF 09-05)
      Poster printed by Les Nouvelles Affiches Cappiello - Atelier D'Art Devambez. Designed by "L. Cappiello. 1924" Sponsored by the U.S. and French presidents with profits to benefit the High Altitude Sanatorium Villages of France and Franco-American social services. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 31, 1953.
    - "National Picture Week". American Art Bureau., [1925] (Folder FF 09-01)
      2 copies. Slightly different formats.
    - "Pictures are Magic Windows". American Art Bureau., undated (Folder FF 09-01)
      Poster designed by Lawson Fenerty. Includes A.A.B.'s slogan, "Beautify with Pictures".
    - Fundraising Appeal to complete the Cathedral of St. John the Divine., [1925] (Folder FF 09-01)
      2 copies. The poster is designed by Adolf Treidler and published by Carey & Sons, N.Y. On back of both copies, in pencil, acquisition date (?) Feb. 28, 1925.
    - B.M.T. Travelguide featuring Whitehall Street Station, 1925 (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster printed by Allied Printing. Advertising for the B.M.T. subway lines. Poster includes a photograph of Fraunces Tavern -- one of the important sites near the Whitehall Street Station. On front, in pencil, "Gift of Mr. Hevlyn D. Benson. Dec. 6, 1935".
    - Safety appeal by the Broadway Merchants Association of Brooklyn, Inc. [BMA]., 1926 (Folder FF 09-01)
      "Save Your Life! Cross At The Crosswalks". Written note on front, "Originated by Hevlyn D. Benson for the B-M-A Safety Drive 1926." On front and on back, in pencil, "Gift of H.D. Benson Dec. 12, 1935".
    - "Sesqui-Centennial Celebration, July 9, 1926" (Provincial Congress of New York's adoption of the Declaration of Independence) (Folder FF 09-01)
      The celebration is under the auspices of the New York State Department of Education and The Westchester County Historical Society. The poster is printed by The Knapp Co., Inc. of New York. Stamped on back, "The Henry A. Ogden Collection of The New York Historical Society October 20, 1936".
    - Congregation Kehilath Israel Announcement of New Location for the High Holidays, [1926] (Folder FF 09-02)
      The congregation relocated from 1162 Jackson Avenue to Crotona Park and Suburban Place into a synagogue designed by Emery Roth. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - "Book Week", 1927 (Folder FF 09-01)
      Book Week ran from November 13th to 19th.
    - The Salvation Army. Maintenance Appeal, 1927 (Folder FF 09-01)
      Appeal for greater New York area. Signed by artist, G. Cary (?).
    - "Lindbergh Flies Alone", [1927?] (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster printed by P.J. Carey & Sons, N.Y. Reprinted editorial from The Sun, May 21, 1927. Aquisiton date (?) on back: "O.T. Barck, Sr. July 8, 1954."
    - Lecture Series for St. John's the Evangelist Church, [1928] (Folder FF 09-01)
      The lecture series included two Sunday evening lectures: one by Will Irwin on Herbert Hoover, A Personality, and one by Sen. Royal S. Copeland on Gov. Alfred E. Smith and The Purpose of Government. On the back, there is some further information about St. John's the Evangelist Church. There is also, in pen, "Gift of Mr. E.B. Child. Feb. 16, 1933".
    - 1928 Presidential Campaign Informational Poster (Folder FF 09-04)
      Poster is copyrighted by The Osborne Company, Newark, New Jersey. The poster advertises the Weber-Bunke-Lange Coal Co. on West 96th Street in New York City. Poster includes photographs of all the U.S. Presidents up to Calvin Coolidge, photographs of the presidential and vice presidential candidates of 1928, and photographs of the White House, Oval Office, and Capitol. The poster also lists the current Senate, The Electoral and the Popular Vote for President, By Parties and States, 1920-1924, and several facts about the Presidency, including salary and minimum age.
    - Haym Salomon Monument Committee., 1929 (Folder FF 09-01)
      Poster seeking donations to erect monument of Haym Salomon, Revolutionary Patriot. The Committee is under the auspices of the Federation of Polish Jews in America. Poster designed by Mitchell Loeb. On back, in pencil, "O.T. Barck, Sr. July 8, 1954".
    - Van Cortlandt House Museum, undated (Folder FF 09-01)